Okay, welcome back everyone.
>> So, um the first assignment is out and
uh as Graham said, we we have credits
available for you to to work on it for
those of you who are enrolled in the
class. Do you folks have any logistic
questions? Cool. Okay. So we talked in
the last lecture about how agents can uh
choose what to retain within their
context window as a way of you know
storing information within a task and
using that to um to determine what's
important to do better within the task.
So a big part of today is going to be
about how can agents go beyond the
context window and store information
across tasks in external stores um that
will be useful for them to improve
performance on tasks in the future. And
this is going to be skill induction. Um,
and uh, we'll build on some some work
that was done in the past on memory
systems for agents. Um, and show how to
apply those to to agents. But there's
also another view on skills. And skills
are a way for people to write
instructions for an agent that can
encode kind of like best practices or
the knowledge that you have about how a
task should be done. And these are
actually going to be complimentary to
each other. Um so we'll cover it just a
small amount in this lecture but um you
can imagine a system that um is sort of
having a human in the loop um that's
relying on the agent to uh propose some
potential best practices from the
experiences that it has a person edit
those and goes back and forth or vice
versa like you know having a skill and
instruction that's written by a person
be refined by the agent based on
experience. So yeah, it's a lot of
different viewpoints, but hopefully by
the end of the lecture, you'll see how
they can all sort of fit together.
So let's just start off with some
motivation about why you might want to
remember things from one task to
another. So say that we have an agent
that's carrying out tasks in a website
like a shopping site and you might give
it a task like add Sony headphones to my
wish list. So when we cover guey agents,
you'll we'll get into the details of,
you know, the representation space, the
action space for how a system like this
works. But at a high level, it's going
to be producing actions like um uh
navigating to the store website, finding
the search box for it, typing some text
in that search box, and then clicking
search. And that's going to be the part
that like searches for the headphones,
right? And then we'll do something with
them. We'll find the ones that match the
request the user had and put them into
our wish list.
We might have another task that we carry
out in the future like find the wireless
keyboard price range. And if we're doing
that on the same site, a lot of the
actions are going to be reused, right?
We'll go to the store, we'll find the
search box, we'll search for the
different product but in a similar way
and then we'll do something different
with it like you know getting the prices
and reporting those back to the user.
But if it's difficult for the agent to
figure out how to do this search, once
it knows how to do it, it should be able
to reuse that knowledge in the future to
be more effective on future tasks.
So a lot of structure recurs and today
is going to be about how can we
represent this shared structure. So for
example, is it best to just uh keep kind
of the raw actions that the agent
produced when it was carrying out this
shared subtask or is it better to try to
abstract it into for example a code
function which could be run as a
blackbox or maybe tested or even like
hierarchically call other functions.
We'll also be interested in how can the
agent like determine which parts of a
task should be reused in the future.
And um as we're you know any time we
have a memory that we're building up
from experience, there's questions about
um how do we grow that memory? Do we are
we always adding to it? What happens if
we get some conflicting information or
we find a better way to do something? We
might want to make edits to it. we might
want to delete things if they no longer
seem to apply. So, how can we um kind of
manage the life cycle of these skills um
and these subtask representations that
are learned?
[snorts]
So, I'd say there's three general ways
that we can get agents to update. So,
the first one we covered in the last
lecture. It's um just what you maintain
in the context window of the model. So
this is um you know in the standard
React style way. It's the history of the
past observations and actions that
you've taken, messages you've gotten
from the user, feedback from the
environment, and you need to you need to
choose like what to retain given kind of
the limitations of the context window
and the model's ability to use that. So
uh we talked a lot about like compaction
and methods for managing what's in that
context window. Today we're going to be
focusing on storing things outside of
the context window. So even with like
really long context windows that we have
now of like a million tokens uh for um
multiple for like carrying out multiple
tasks with an agent um you're going to
exceed that context window and you want
to remember things from past tasks to
help you on future ones. So if we are
storing things outside of the window, um
that's going to look something like a
database um that needs to be managed um
in some some way or um like a file
system that the agent can access. And uh
this lecture is going to be about
methods for um putting things into those
types of storage and um using them and
updating them. And then the final way is
going to be like actually making uh
updates to the weights of the model.
Right? So this looks more like standard
supervised fine-tuning or reinforcement
learning. We'll cover that in a few
lectures later on. But each of these has
like pros and cons. So um I think like a
main pro of using external artifacts is
that they're like they can be ported
across models, right? So if you um have
a description of the way to search for a
product um that could be used by any one
of a number of different models um
within an agent framework. Whereas if
you're actually making updates to the
weights of the model that's just an
update for that specific model and it
doesn't transfer to others. So external
artifacts are also more inspectable by
people. Um, so you could write down best
practices or how to search on a site.
The agent can use that. The agent could
also propose, you know, kind of text for
that and you could look at it and make
changes to it. So there's it's easier to
kind of like have an interface between
the person and the system if your um
method of updating, if your method of
remembering is interpretable.
Any questions about this?
How many folks have uh have used skills
in their interactions with the coding
agent? Like how many of you Okay, so
most folks have. How many of you are are
writing the skill yourself?
Okay, so maybe about half the folks who
are using skills. How many of you have
uh gotten an agent to write a skill for
you? Okay, so a lot of folks actually
have. Yeah. What are some things that
what how what's your experience been for
the agent writing the skills? How often
have you been able to use it just right
out of the box? The thing that the agent
constructs
anyone have any spectacular failure
cases or spectacular successes? So just
repeating that for the recording like
sometimes the models will write too much
in the skill like they'll kind of
overinfer the what should be done and
then when that's handed off to another
model it will kind of follow it to the
letter and do a lot more than you
actually wanted it to.
>> Any other examples from folks?
>> Cool. Oh yeah, go ahead. I mean in cases
when you're like trying to like a
production issue for like a particular
system if you give it like three or four
support
and you tell it that look at how people
have this issue in the past create a
skill for yourself
other agents could use to it in the same
way
>> and that's
very
>> oh nice
>> okay cool yeah so instructing it to like
get write the instructions for another
agent it's good enough it's sort of like
simulating what the agent would do.
Yeah, that's interesting. I've sometimes
found that the models are like pretty
bad at kind of like simulating the
theory of mind that you know another
person or an agent would have when they
like look at instructions, but they get
a lot better when you prompt them to do
that. Cool.
Okay.
Yeah. So, a few different like types of
experience that we might want to retain
for agents. So the first is like the
episode and this is you know just the
sequence of observations that you get
from the environment from the user and
the actions that are taken and this is
sort of like the maximum fidelity right
you're just you're retaining everything
you have all the specifics of that
particular environment and the
particular instructions that the user
gave also going to be like the most
costly right it'll need the most tokens
to represent and you probably don't need
all of that right? Like uh just like
when we're doing you know supervised
learning we don't want to retain every
detail we want to abstract to the things
that matter to generalize um in the
future.
So we could also retain some facts like
um some knowledge about the environment
um or about the user and in the early
work on memory systems uh a lot of it
was focused on retaining facts. So like
a user is interacting with an assistant
and maybe gives some personal
information like how old they are or
where they live. The system can retain
that in its memory and then use that
fact to improve future interactions. If
you've um used uh like Anthropic or
Chatbt's uh memory systems, uh they're
doing this basically, right? Like you
can go into the settings, you can view
the memory that they have about you and
there's, you know, a text representation
there from a model that's produced those
facts um from your past interactions.
Looks a little bit like compaction in
some way. It's generated by an LLM. It
gets stored in this external thing.
And then the final one is more specific
to agents. So it's about like how do you
do part of a task um in a way that's
abstracted from the details of the task.
So like in the example we looked at
before, how do you search for products
on a particular website without maybe
retaining the details of searching, you
know, the particular product that you
searched for? And so there's a lot of
choices about how you would represent a
skill. Is it just text? Is it kind of
the actual actions that you took? Um or
could it even be code?
And of course, skills are only going to
be useful if you're going to be doing
the same subtask more than once.
So we could think about like um memory
and skills and the intersection between
them. So memory is just something that
we're saving from the agents
interaction. So for example, what's a
previous product that you purchased on a
site? A skill would be reusable
knowledge about how to act in an
environment. um which could be
represented in one of a variety of ways.
Like it could be, you know, if you're
releasing a um application um by pushing
it to production, here's a checklist
that you need to go through before you
do that. So, a skill could be written by
a person like in this example. But we
could also have um a combination of
memory and skills. So we could induce
skills from the agents past experiences
and store those um and then use those to
hopefully do better in the future. So if
the agent searched successfully for a
product in the past um and uh yeah and
if it was successful, if we think that
it was successful, then we could pull
out something that looks like a skill to
guide the agent in the future. And we'll
get a lot more concrete about what this
looks like through the rest of the
lecture.
So we can think about skills as
instructions where uh skills as
instructions might be written by a
person um for encoding their own you
know preferences or might be
organization policies like this is the
way that we write and test code in this
particular company. Um and human
authored skills um we know where they
came from. we have more maybe control
over the quality but it takes you know a
lot of time to write them and to
maintain them. If we're learning skills
then the agent is producing them. Um and
this is helpful because we can do this
in an automated way. Maybe we can have
like a loop where we induce the skill.
We try to use the skill to redo the same
tasks. We see if things get better on a
metric. Um, but it can be, you know,
potentially noisy too and have, you
know, especially if you're using the
skills for some other agent like we
talked about in those examples everybody
gave, um, it could maybe have unintended
consequences too.
Okay, so let's talk first about uh,
humanridden skills and um, the standards
for these and the ways that they're used
in incurrent agents. So probably a lot
of it sounds like a lot of you have
experience with this already. Uh so
maybe you've been using these in the
context of an example kind of like this.
Uh there's this nice blog post from open
hands that has guidance on using skills.
Um for those of you who um who haven't
used skills yet or if you you know like
some suggestions on how to uh how to
have best practices for creating and
using skills. But they have this
motivating motivating example of say
that you find yourself like always
giving similar instructions to a coding
agent. Um so you um want the you want to
check the code that has been written
using one of a couple different
llinters. You want to give type hints.
You want to use a particular type of
dock strings. And you want to apply
piest to all the functions. So if you're
always doing this, you could always type
this guidance into the system. Um, but
you know, a kind of natural and faster
way to do this would be to just have the
like store the guidance as a text file
and then have the agent use that
guidance um as an instruction. So you
should reach for a skill when you want
to do something repeatedly following
kind of like a fixed specification. And
the agent's going to choose how to
interpret this specification in context,
but the um general instruction is the
same.
And the way that this is implemented in
the current standard for skills um which
is called agent skills is just as a
collection of files which the agent is
able to read.
And here's an example of of that. So if
we are constructing a skill for Python
review um we'll have a folder which has
a structure like this. So skills have
this standard structure where they'll
have a skill.md file and you have to
have that. Skill.md um is a markdown
file that starts with um some YAML
metadata. So you need to have a name for
the skill and you need to have a short
description uh which is going to give
guidance to the language model about
when the skill should be applied. And
we'll see in a slide or two about how
the model gets access to this
information in the YAML header. And then
um after the header you'll have a much
more detailed description of um how the
skill should be applied which would for
example you know list um here are all
the llinters that you should apply
here's how testing should be done and so
on. So you have to have skill.mmd. You
also have a few other um folders which
are optional but can contain some extra
resources for the agent to use as it
carries out the skill. So there's
scripts which has executable code. So
for example, if you had like a Python
script that would run a llinter, you
could put it in there and then describe
it in this skill.md file. There's also
references, which would be sort of like
supplementary documentation that maybe
you don't you you don't need to use it
every time you use the skill. Um, but
you'll have maybe a reference to that
documentation in the skill file. The
agent could load it as needed from the
references folder. And then assets
basically just has like, you know,
additional templates or resources like
if you're, you know, doing something
that involves like Ginga and you need
the agent to load that conditionally.
So this can be a lot of information,
right? And we um don't want to fill up
the context window of the model um with
all of the possible skills that it could
use. So there's a mechanism called
progressive disclosure which is going to
just show relevant parts of skills to
the agent as they're needed. So the
first level is um the metadata in this
YAML file. Uh so the name and the
description and that's always going to
be um shown to the model in the system
prompt if the skill is loaded if it's
available to the model to use. So you
need to be kind of concise in this uh
description. Um so that if you have a
lot of skills you don't fill things up
too much.
There's the second level which is the
rest of the text in the markdown file
and um that'll be loaded conditionally
if the model decides that the skill is
relevant um and uh decides to read the
rest of the file via a tool call. We'll
see an example of that in a minute. And
then the next level is sort of like all
the resources in here which will also be
loaded um using tool calls. So you kind
of need to have enough information in
the skill.md file for the model to be
aware that it should look into these
additional folders to get more resources
um when it's carrying out the skill. Any
questions about this and you'll
implement this in assignment one or
maybe some of you are already starting
on implementing that.
>> Yeah.
are so high
like what if that takes too much of that
effect performance?
>> Yeah. So if you have a lot of skills
even if the skill metadata is pretty
short could it affect performance? Yeah,
it definitely can. Um so you want to
keep the number of skills somewhat small
and maybe just load them conditionally.
um in one of the state-of-the-art
agents, Hermes agent, I think the I'm
not sure the number of skills, but like
the total length of the skill
descriptions in the system prompt is
like 3,000 tokens. Um there's some
papers that we'll see in a little bit
that show that if you have too many
skills, um it can make performance
worse. Like adding in irrelevant skills
can drop performance um because, you
know, the context gets longer. The model
might be distracted by things that are
actually irrelevant. So yeah, you
definitely need to be careful about the
number of skills, but um I think it
would be pretty rare to have like 10,000
or a thousand skills. Generally, it's,
you know, smaller and you would maybe
load skills as needed for like the
software tasks that you're carrying out.
>> Yeah.
>> How sensitive are those triggers?
>> Yeah, that's a great question. How
sensitive are the triggers? So the the
triggers will be tool calls that will be
generated by the model. And so whether
they get called or not is a function is
totally dependent on the model. Um and
you know the model's ability to predict
that it should be triggered based on the
past context and what it knows about the
skill. So that you know depends on the
model depends on the description you
write and um that's why we need
evaluations for this. Um and one of the
papers that we'll look at takes a step
in that direction.
>> Yeah.
like a standardized name.
>> Yeah. Uh skill.md is a standardized
name. So the the standard is called the
um I think the agent skills standard and
um you like models agents are trained to
to use that agent frameworks are trained
to load that. Um so yeah you um if you
want to use an alternate format well
first put it you know as close to this
as you can but you could do you know if
you have particular if you have
particular um things that you want like
in the references folder you could
describe them in skill.md and like all
this is just going to be instructions to
the language model so it could be robust
to other configurations also especially
if you describe them.
>> Yeah. Why are
>> Yeah, why markdown? It it is a balance
of machine and human readability, I
think.
>> Yeah, that's a great question. Could
there be better formats than than
skill.md?
Yeah. Do you have things in mind?
I think like um so uh I mean it's just
like linear right um it's you can have
hyperlinks which is good you can embed
images too um
>> yeah um but uh like it's difficult to
you know represent things that are
dynamic so like maybe you want to
illustrate to the model like um
different ways the data could be
visualized um you know maybe that would
be better with like a JavaScript
interactive JavaScript application or
something like that. Um, yeah, you
could, you know, have that be sort of
like a code file here that gets
executed. Um, but and maybe like
referenced in the markdown. Um, so I
think like markdown is sort of the best
attempt at having something that's
general and like readable, but then you
would rely on the language model to
interpret other formats.
>> I think in the scientific literature
that uh Daniel's going to talk about,
there's basically two ways. There's
textual skills and programmatic skills
and the textual skills appear in the
markdown and the programmatic skills
appear in the script. So it kind of it's
pretty broad if you consider those.
>> Yeah. Cool.
>> Yeah.
>> Does anyone do
to not have to put it all in context?
For example, if you're making an agent
that modifies cloud infrastructure, you
work at some big bank and have a billion
things in AWS and it would be nice to be
able to just ask the model to modify
something, but then because it's a
billion things, you can just have a
billion tools for every small component
available. Yes.
>> So looks like something
would
do. Yeah, definitely in some of the
research papers that so the question was
like do people retrieve from large
collections of skills. Um and yeah
definitely in some of the research
papers that we'll look at um they do
that um either using you know just like
a text embedding based retrieval or
doing something that's more kind of like
domain conditional like we know these
skills apply to this site so when we're
interacting with that site we'll load
those skills. Yeah, I imagine production
systems do this too, but um yeah, I
don't have any references off the top of
my head for that. Cool. Okay, so we'll
uh just uh kind of quickly to show you
how progressive disclosure works. Um we
first need to give the model access to
this level one, right? Let it know what
skills are available. And you'll have a
system prompt that looks something like
this. This is just taken from Hermes
agent which is sort of like a standard
open- source um agent that is able to
use and induce skills and you'll um kind
of describe what skills are. Uh you'll
tell the model about this skill view
tool which it could use to read the rest
of the markdown file and then you'll
list out all the skills that you have.
So there's just two skills here. Um,
there's a code quality skill and a
workflow skill. And that's just the YAML
metadata from those skill files.
So, um, the model is able to use tool
calls to, you know, expand the rest of
the skill. And here's what that might
look like. So, it always has the index
of skills in the system prompt, but it
could choose to make a tool call to open
the Python review skill. um if that
seems relevant to you know the user
asked for a review of some Python code
and then it's going to like um you know
get that markdown file insert it as a
message to the system as an observation
the result of that skill view tool. Um
the system might choose to run something
from the scripts directory um and then
it'll get the result of running that
script as an observation put it in the
window um and might choose to you know
like view additional files within that
skill package.
Okay. So yeah, we these questions that
we had about like you know could
additional skills hurt um are skills
being triggered in the right place. Uh
we answer questions like this by
building evaluations and um the the work
on this is a little bit um new. It's
sort of ongoing but um a really great
first effort in the space is called
skills bench and what they do is they um
collect a bunch of skills uh from uh
various sources online. they actually
get like 2 million skills. Um, and
they'll also have people write tasks
which seem like they could benefit from
skills. Uh, and so they'll like get 400
tasks and um those are going to be
written independently from the skills,
but they'll have the task annotators
choose from this pool of skills ones
that seem like they could apply to the
tasks. And so you'll have kind of like a
small set of curated skills. um and
you'll supply those skills to an agent
as it's trying to solve the task and
they'll evaluate this on like um you
know four different agent frameworks uh
with I think like 18 models something
like that and they'll just see like does
having the skills um improve performance
over not having the skills across all
the tasks for a given agent framework
and model combination right so this will
evaluate you know it'll implicitly
evaluate the skill quality but will be
designed to evaluate is a model and
framework able to you know use the
skills appropriately and they're trying
to choose the skills. So they have like
a filter um which checks to see that for
a small subset of models the performance
on the tasks does improve when you give
models access to the skills and then
you're seeing if that's also true for
kind of a wider set of frameworks and
models.
Yeah.
Does the general setup make sense? Cool.
So on average, you know, with this cur
curated set of um skills, uh the average
pass rates on these tasks using like
humanridden verification criteria does
increase. And so you can see like the
solid bars to the shaded bars across a
bunch of different models um and
frameworks. Um but actually uh ski like
tasks that require fewer skills to solve
benefit more from having the skills
available than ones that require more
skills. Um and so this is partly a
difficulty thing but also partly that
the models might be getting distracted
by having more skills available. And you
could imagine that it's getting much
worse with like a much larger number of
skills. Um we'll see some more evidence
for that later on in the lecture.
And actually skills still hurt on a
number of the tasks for particular model
types. Um so the model might be using
the skill inappropriately which could
actually make it do the task in a way
different than what the person
specified. So this kind of motivates the
importance of like checking to see if
the skills that you wrote are actually
making your outputs better.
So skills can come from, you know, a
bunch of different sources. They could
be bundled with the harness. Um, they
could be written by a person. Um, and a
lot of you have done this, it sounds
like, and you then, you know, kind of
install it in a in a way that's
specified by the framework that you're
using, but they can also be created by
the agent. And, um, Hermes has a skill
manage tool. um open hands as a skill
creator uh command that help work you
through the process of creating a skill.
And when you're creating a skill, I
think it's really important to base that
skill on some prior interactions that
you've had rather than trying to just do
it sort of a priori. Um and actually
there's some results in the skills bench
paper that show that models when they're
tasked to create a skill by themselves
just based on a task description,
they're really bad at it. and it
actually makes performance worse. So, as
a person, you're probably better because
you kind of like know the way that you
want it to be done, but it's generally
best to base it on, you know, past
things that you've done because when
you're doing a task, it'll reveal some
things about the way you want it to be
done that you might not know in advance.
So there's a nice case study of this um
from the open hands blog post on how do
you like so you have this code review
skill that you've created. How do you
check and see if it's working and then
improve it if necessary.
So this is focused on like reviewing
poll requests and what what you could do
is like um after the review is produced
by the agent then a person is going to
go through the poll request and look at
each of those review comments and either
address them or not. And you can apply a
modelbased judge after that and count up
how many of these were like actually
used by the person which will give you a
sense of how good the pull request was.
And you can like um do this over a large
number of pull requests that were
created and then reviewed by the agent
using this skill. And um if you do this
over um you know like hundreds or
thousands of examples, you'll get a lot
of evidence about what's working and
what's not, you can summarize all of
that with a reasoning model um and use
that to like for example identify that
it's not helpful to um you know produce
code that ignores the repo conventions.
people did like incorporate those
changes quite a bit. And then you could
like have the model propose some updates
to the skill file that will make the you
know reviews produced by the system more
likely to be incorporated by the person.
Cool. Any questions before we move on?
Okay.
So next we'll talk about how do we get
models to automatically remember things
from their past experience and then
we'll use that to like build on um to
talk about inducing skills from
experience.
So this is this is an old paper. This is
from 2023 um but it was pretty
influential. Um and it's uh it's one of
the first papers it's called MEMGPT.
It's one of the first papers to uh
[snorts]
introduce a way that you can manage
memory outside of the context window of
a language model. So this is like a
really a systems inspired paper. I think
we talked about a couple lectures ago
about you know kind of having like
memory hierarchies like you know
something that is fast to access which
for the language model is the context
window and then something that's like
larger but but slower and in this
setting that would be like an external
store of of facts and back when this
paper was written uh a few years ago
context windows were even shorter like
you know 8,000 tokens um so this sort of
approach was really well motivated even
for just interacting with like an
assistant system. Um nowadays you know
our context windows are larger but what
you want to store in them is also much
larger. So this sort of approach is
pretty well motivated for agents too.
But the basic idea here is that you're
going to have like a um you'll have you
know the system instructions which don't
get updated. you'll have a working
context um which is going to uh pull
things from an external memory um and
also you'll be storing things to this
external memory and those reads and
writes are going to be controlled by
tool calls from the model
and um you'll also you know have like a
separate storage for the actual messages
that the system received um but that's
going to be controlled in a pretty
similar way to this uh this memory over
fax
So, what this actually looks like, sorry
it's a little bit hard to read with the
brightness in here, but like if you um
you might uh have an interaction with
the model where the user like mentions
six flags and um the system could
produce a tool call that searches within
this storage for past mentions of six
flags from its past interactions. It'll
take those and it'll put them into this
like working context. Um and then the
model um this working context is stored
within the context window of the
language model. So the model will be
able to use those as it outputs its
response.
But it's important to be able to do more
than just like add to memory because for
example like um maybe you're talking to
the system about your job. you say I
work at X, but then if you change jobs
later on, you want the system to be able
to like use the latest information.
And um this paper called me zero uh
introduces a way for memories to be
updated as well. Um so the way that this
works is you'll have like messages
coming in and um each time you get a
message, you'll apply a language model
to extract some memories from it. um
some like potential facts that you might
want to store or update and you'll have
an external uh database store um and
you'll try to check and see do I have
anything in that database store that's
relevant to these um facts that I pulled
out of these messages. So you'll
retrieve the top K and to do this you'll
use like an embedding based retriever
model like you know the ones we talked
about a little bit ago. um you'll pull
out similar facts like um six flags for
example or like um I work at X and
you'll apply a language model to check
for all of these extracted memories from
these latest messages um do they um are
they present in these similar retrieved
memories? If they're not present then we
should potentially add them in. um if
they are an update to something that's
there, we should replace what's stored
for that with the new thing. If it
negates something that's already there,
like for example, you say, "I work at
X," but then later on you say, "I got
laid off," you might want to just delete
that fact rather than um than updating
it. Um or if it's not relevant at all,
you would just ignore it.
And um I'll refer you to details or for
the paper for for details about this um
because the details also change with
with agentive systems but I think the
idea that um it's useful to be able to
like update knowledge as well if you
have conflicts is potentially pretty
useful.
So, um, does anybody remember something
from the lecture on context management
that had a similar goal to this being
able to update or delete memory?
Yeah.
Uh, hashing.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Basically, does anybody
remember the specific paper?
Yeah. Yeah, it's hashing in the sense
that there we had like key values and
queries, right? Um and we were like
storing values which were vectors. Um
here we're storing like text um as
facts.
Yeah.
So the Delta paper actually did this,
right? like um linear attention is only
able to append um values to your um
what's effectively your memory but Delta
um uh like effectively retrieves um
things that are stored for particular
queries and then changes them changes
the vectors that are stored for for them
and that helps improve performance. So
this is sort of like a textbased analog
of that that has a similar goal.
Yeah, you could also think about like um
for the third type of learning for
updating the weights of a model, it's
potentially helpful there to be able to
forget stuff also. Um especially if you
have kind of like conflicting knowledge
and and people are starting to develop
some approaches for that like unlearning
um is one way to do it.
Okay, so those are some foundational
papers about memory um that were
developed for assistance
for agents. Um feedback on trajectories
can be really useful. So this paper
called reflection was um a really
impactful it's a really uh it's a really
pretty simple but effective um the way
to get agents to use feedback and
potentially do better. So, it's
definitely worth knowing about. It's a
good thing to implement if you're
working on a project that might want an
agent to be able to benefit from its
past experiences. Um, and the way it
works is we're trying to improve the
performance of an agent given multiple
attempts on a particular task. So, say
that you're asking the agent to like um,
you know, search for a product on a
website. It makes one attempt at it. um
it says that it's finished and you're
able to get some feedback about whether
it was likely correct or not. So that
could come from like a person looking at
it. It could come from applying a model
as a judge. Um but given that feedback,
you'll want the model to try again and
try to do better.
And what this paper does is show that
natural language feedback um on the
attempt can be a really helpful thing
for the model to condition on in its
second attempt. So like if it's trying
to answer this question about what was a
particular series of battles, it might
just mention one particular battle and
then the feedback that's given um
generated by a language model based on
knowing this is incorrect and looking at
the question and the answer might be um
you gave just a single battle rather
than a series. So as you can imagine
this would be really helpful feedback
for the model to condition on as it you
know does another attempt at this task
and it can get it correct. Um and the
paper shows that you know conditioning
on this natural language description of
what went wrong can be really helpful.
So we can generalize this also to um the
agent improving as it does different
tasks. Right? This is improving on the
same task. But you could imagine um
feedback might be generally helpful to
improve performance on similar tasks as
long as the feedback's like sufficiently
general.
And the final way that we can like um
have agents uh improve or you know kind
of the final foundational thing for
helping agents improve um is remembering
trajectories uh like entire
trajectories, entire episodes that
they've done in the past and using that
to shape what they do on future tasks.
There is a bunch of papers that have
done this. We have some links to them at
the bottom of this slide. Um, but the
key thing in all of them is you'll have
some collection of like training tasks
and those tasks could be like a
collection of demonstrations or they
could be produced by the agent as it's
carrying out tasks one at a time. Um,
and you'll pull all of those tasks
together. Maybe you'll additionally like
um generate some text that describes uh
feedback from them sort of like
reflection did on the last slide. And
you'll have that pool of experiences.
And then when you get a new task um that
comes in, you'll retrieve from this uh
set of trajectories and um maybe
generated text about them to find
something that's relevant for the task
that you're carrying out. You'll put it
in the context window of your model and
it'll generally help you to do better.
Um so this is sort of like rag for
agents, right? Um and uh it's pretty
effective.
Any questions about this?
Yeah.
>> What do you mean by trajectory in this
case is like sequence of calls.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So a trajectory generally
for an agent is the sequence of um like
messages that it gets from the
environment or the user. So the
observations um the actions that it
takes like the tool calls and um and uh
potentially also you know the chains of
thought that it produces. So one way to
think about it is basically just like
all the sequence of um of uh messages um
in the context window of the model
>> and you retrieve it by image
differently. You can do this regular
embedding retrieval or compare to
process sequences and do some set
comparison.
>> Yeah. What are the different ways that
you could do retrieval? So typically you
want the model to you're giving the
model the description of a new task that
it should carry out. So you have just
that text description and you'll embed
that um with an embedding model and
you'll retrieve um based on the
descriptions of other tasks that each
have like a trajectory associated with
them and maybe you'll also constrain
that to be like we'll just retrieve the
tasks for this particular domain that
we're working in. Um yeah, good
question. Any other questions about this
approach? Generally, this is sort of
like a whole class of approaches. Um
there's different ways to instantiate
it. Um the details like how do you build
up the experiences? How do you do the
retrieval? Um but just want to kind of
give you a sense that if we have past
successful trajectories and we show
those as examples to the agent, it can
help it to do better.
Okay. So with that we kind of have the
foundation for talking about um actually
inducing skills. Um so
we can think about skills as being like
parts of a task that are reusable across
different tasks. So at the very
beginning we talked about like searching
for a product and that might look
something like we tell the agent show me
results for this particular query and
the agent might produce a chain of
thought like this and then it might
produce these particular actions that
actually interact with the web page like
um uh clicking on this element
identified by this particular ID which
is the search box typing a query in
there and and clicking on another
element which is like the actual button
to search.
And this uh chunk of a task might be
reused on future tasks. Like if I say
what is the price range for um this
particular item, it might need to do
these same exact steps again as well as
some additional ones afterwards.
And so we can think of a skill as being
um a specific like reused part of the
task.
Is this a good way to represent a skill?
Can anybody think of any issues with
this?
>> Yeah.
just
>> Yeah,
that's right. Yeah. So, like if the
element ids on the page change, the
skill will break. And you know, there's
a number of ways that that could happen.
Like, you know, maybe the elements are
maybe it's the same page, but things are
just numbered differently. You can make
some changes to the action space to deal
with that. I think JY will talk about
that in his lecture. But like if we go
to a different website that has like a
different search interface um it's going
to break and we'll see some examples of
that later on.
Yeah. So we'll generally compare as
Graham said text versus code as ways to
represent skills.
I want to briefly highlight some uh
really cool papers um from the past that
I think kind of like lay a foundation
for skill induction um for learning
skills from experience. Uh, one is
called um Voyager and um they're
controlling an agent in Minecraft. Um,
and they're using uh code as a way to
control the agent where the code
functions um implement things like um
crafting a particular item or combating
a zombie. And representing these like
subtasks as functions allows functions
to call each other. So that as the agent
like learns functions for simple things,
it can then like compose them calling
them in other functions and you can
carry out increasingly complex tasks.
There's also a line of work um from the
program induction community um that that
does this. I think a really nice
representative of this is um uh work
called dreamcoder and a few papers that
built on it. And there you're um sort of
uh you have basically like grammarss
over things that you're constructing um
like objects um and you uh like have uh
some examples of complete objects which
are constructed using like very
low-level functions and you search for
recurrent patterns in that you find
patterns that can be abstracted into
functions and you do that repeatedly and
you're sort of like compressing the
programs that construct these objects.
And then there's also some follow-ups to
this that uh integrate like large
language models, Python code, and uh
natural language descriptions too.
And some of the same ideas in those
papers are also useful for agents that
are um using language models to interact
with the world. A typical way that we'll
evaluate systems for inducing and using
skills is an online learning setting. So
when you're interacting with um an
agent, you are maybe having it carry out
a bunch of tasks in succession and some
of those tasks are going to be similar
to each other. You want the system to be
able to learn from your interactions
with it and then be able to do better in
the future, right? So um this is an
online learning setting where we'll have
tasks come in one at a time. So for
example, like you might say, add a Sony
Bluetooth headphone to my wish list. And
we'll be building up a memory of skills
um incrementally as we solve those
tasks. So um there will be an induction
step that we'll talk about in a slide or
two. And that induction step will
create a skill like search for a product
and add a product to the wish list that
are useful for solving this particular
task.
And um you know maybe we have another
one like this task here and we can apply
those skills on future tasks like this
task might also involve searching for a
product and hopefully we'll do better on
that task given that we had this skill
induced from the previous task
and so on. So what we're interested in
is if we can measure success on each of
these tasks, is our success rate like
getting better and better? Are we able
to solve increasingly complex tasks um
as we're learning from experience and
building up um uh representations of the
ways to do these simpler tasks? Any
questions about this setting?
Okay, cool.
So the papers that we'll look at for the
rest of the lecture look at sort of
different parts of this space of um uh
learning skills from experience having
this library and ask questions about
what should we do with the skills like
after we've um induced them. So there's
generally like a learning step where
we'll have these uh tasks coming in.
We'll try to get a skill out of them.
will decide whether to store that skill
um in the memory that we're building up
over time. There's um the step of like
actually using this memory of skills to
potentially improve performance on the
tasks that we're carrying out. And then
finally, we might want to, you know, if
we're getting too many skills, we might
want to try to simplify those, like
delete the ones that aren't being used,
or if they're too specific, we might
want to make them more general. um or
like consolidate and merge multiple
things together.
[clears throat]
We'll go a little bit deeper into one
paper um that I think is pretty
representative of ways for inducing
skills. Uh it was also done here at CMU
as work led by Zora Wong who will be
giving a guest lecture on some other
topics a little bit later on in the
course. Um but this paper's called agent
workflow memory and um the way it works
is it we applied it to web tasks. Uh
this is work with with Graham also um
and me and uh we applied this to web
tasks and you have a query like this and
you know tell me the number of reviews
that our store received so far and when
the agent's carrying this out these are
the actual tool calls that it'll
produce.
So we have this sequence of tool calls
and we want to try to identify which
parts of this might be potentially
reusable in the future
and you can probably guess how we do
this. We ask a language model to take a
look at the sequence of tool calls and
identify ones that seem like they might
be useful on future tasks.
And we'll have the model output what we
call workflows um which are sort of like
a textbased representation of skills
text and actions. And a workflow will
have like a description of the subtask
like searching for a particular item.
And then um it'll have the sequence of
actions that you use to do that. And
we're having the model make this a
little bit more general so that it could
apply to like searching for other terms.
So we have it use like create a template
that can abstract out some parts of the
um initial action sequence. You might be
thinking like this is starting to look
like code, right? That's true. Um and a
little bit later on we'll compare code
to this also and show how that can be
better in some ways but also uh make
things a little bit more uh fragile.
A pretty important part of this is we'll
um apply a judge model to this
trajectory to decide um have the judge
predict whether the trajectory seem to
be correct or not. And we'll use that to
determine whether we should actually add
the workflows that were induced to the
memory. Um because we don't want to be
um remembering things that were
incorrect because those might steer the
model wrong in the future.
>> Any questions about this?
Okay. And
so
the way that we'll um give the model
access to these uh collection of
workflows um is just by sticking them in
the context window of the model. So this
looks a lot like you know this agent
skill standard. Um you have choices
about whether you show everything or
whether you show just you know kind of
the text description. um and what you do
there could depend on how many skills
you have and you know the context length
of the model.
So um for the sake of time I I'll skip
over this induction prompt but we do
find that um having this memory of like
past uh subtasks um can help to improve
the performance of the agent as it's
learning online. So on the x-axis here
we have like um different tasks in a
fixed ordering from this benchmark
involving interacting with like a map
tool and the blue line here is the
baseline agent that doesn't have a
memory that sort of converges to around
you know like 10% accuracy on these
tasks and the labels here are the tasks
that are being solved by the agent
correctly. Um and then this black line
which adds in this memory of um subtasks
improves pretty substantially and it's
able to um you know this gap emerges
between the two but it's also able to
carry out these like increasingly
complex tasks eventually doing things
like you know finding a hotel near this
location showing me the walking path um
that the baseline agent just isn't able
to do.
So this is using, you know, sort of this
mix of text and example actions to
represent skills.
But we could also consider using code,
right? And both of these are
implementations of a search product um
function. And
if we're using just this text and
examples, this is going to be in the
context window of the model. and then
it's going to be needing to produce
these tool calls um in a new context,
right? As it tries to carry out the same
subtask. So, it's flexible like the
model could choose to insert a
particular search term to search for a
different product. If the website has
changed and we no longer have like this
particular um element for the search
box, then the agent could choose to use
the correct one instead. Um, but it also
means that the agent needs to like
actually produce all of those tool calls
itself. If we're using code, the agent
could actually just call this function
as a tool, right? If it passes in the
right arguments and if the functions
correct, then it doesn't have to do
anything. It doesn't have to produce all
of those low-level actions itself. Um,
the tool will just do that as it
executes in the environment. Can anybody
think of uh some pros and cons of using
a function like this as a representation
for a skill?
Any cons?
>> It's very rigid.
>> Yeah, it is very rigid. So like um the
model will need to the model calling
this tool will do exactly these three
steps and there's no room to to deviate
from it. Um yes that's a main call
that's a main like con to it but we also
get a lot of the pros of using code
right so like we can nest functions it
can be hierarchical we can actually like
generate test cases for that specific
function too independent from the entire
trajectory that it's executed in. And we
can do things like you know refactoring
also.
So uh Zora has another paper um called
inducing programmatic skills or agent
skill induction which um which do this
and it looks pretty similar to the
approach we were using to induce these
textual workflows. So you have a
trajectory like this with these tool
calls and we'll have the language model
um we'll we'll just use the fact that
language models are also good at
generating code and we'll um prompt the
model to generate functions which
abstract a lot of the um uh behaviors in
this trajectory and these are real
examples. So the language model will
write this search reviews function and
um a doc string for it and then you know
it has these low-level tool calls as um
lines in the function. This other one
for open marketing reviews but we'll
also have it generate sort of a rewrite
of this original trajectory that uses
those tools. So a really nice thing
about um code is that we can test it by
executing it. So instead of applying the
judge to the original trajectory like we
did before, we can have the language
model. Well, we can execute this
generated abstracted code and then apply
the judge to the end result that you get
from that. And if that appears to be
correct, that's sort of like a stronger
indicator that the skills, these code
skills that you induced are also
correct.
And if they are, then we put them in the
memory and they become usable to the
language model just as tools. So this is
a way of like building up a tool library
that the model's able to use on future
examples and um we show that it also you
know improves performance.
Any questions about that?
Yeah. So a nice thing about um code
skills is that they allow testing just
of the skill by itself. Um there's this
nice paper called skillw weaver which
does this. Um, so this is sort of some
pseudo code for the uh the loop that I
just showed you where you have a task,
you um propose some set of like code
skills for it and then you'll try to use
those skills to execute the task. You'll
get an episode, you'll apply a reward
model to it. Um, and if it succeeds,
then you can put all those induced
skills into your memory. But if not,
then you could make some revisions to
it. And there's a number of ways that
skills might not succeed, right? So, um,
one thing we could do is like apply a
code llinter to an induced skill. So,
here's a real example from the paper.
There's this induced skill called
identify pill. Um, you know, for like
interacting with a drug website. And
this uh function like takes a lot of
arguments like you know the um the make
of the pill the color but in the initial
version of this skill that the agent
wrote it actually didn't use all the
parameters. So like it ignored this
color parameter. So you could get
feedback from a llinter on this skill
and then sort of in the reflection type
way um condition on that and then like
you know uh create an updated version of
the function and store that or like try
executing that and store that. You could
also use feedback from this reward model
and condition on that when you're um
making these revisions to the skill 2.
So these are some nice benefits of code
um that can be advantages even if you
know the actual code function itself is
a bit more rigid.
Another nice benefit is that because
these functions that are induced are now
tool calls, it can really reduce the
number of times that your agent needs to
interact with the environment. So here's
an example from um Zora's uh ASI paper.
We have this uh task like uh updating a
couple addresses on a page and for the
base agent you have to you know like do
all the very low-level actions of
navigating through all these forms
typing the particular um things from the
address. But if we have this model that
has induced these code skills, you can
and this is a real example from uh from
the work where we induce this navigate
to address settings and update address
details functions. We can actually solve
this task in three steps where we um you
know assuming that this is a good fit
for the site. Um we can just call these
two functions and um complete the task.
Um, and the agent is actually much
faster because it doesn't need to
reobserve the website and then generate
the tool call, then reobserve the new
website, generate the new tool call. Um,
as you'll probably see in the guey um,
lecture that JY is giving, um, a really
big bottleneck for these models is
actually the number of times that they
have to interact with the site because
these images take up a lot of tokens and
actually producing a chain of thought
um, before each action takes up a lot of
tokens too. All of those have to be
generated. So efficiency is really
important here.
And um in this work we did find so we
did a controlled comparison between
using text skills and code skills. This
was on a set of tasks which did have
sort of more repeated structure. Um but
we found that uh in comparison to no
memory text skills um helped but code
skills helped even more in terms of you
know the accuracy of the system but also
we got pretty big improvements in
efficiency the number of times that the
agent needed to interact with the page.
Cool.
So, as we've kind of talked about
before, a big potential issue with
skills is that they might not be
general. And here's a failure case of
this approach and actually a failure
case of these code skills. So, we tried
to see how well could skills generalize
across websites. And we induced um these
code skills on one site uh and then we
tried to apply them on a real website uh
like the Target shopping site. So this
skill um that was induced on a different
site worked on that site but like um
uses assumes that this uh this um
particular element that you're
interacting with has a drop down like
this. Whereas on the target site it's
you know this set of radio buttons and
so it it fails there. And um you have to
have the model be able to like actually
edit the skill based on um feedback from
the environment as it's interacting with
it.
But code has a solution to this, right?
Uh so we have um abstract classes and
those can be instantiated in different
ways. There's this uh paper called poly
skill which does this. So um they're
using code as the representation sort of
building on this ASI work that we did.
Um, but the first time that the model
interacts with a new website, it writes
an abstract class which doesn't have
implementations for the methods, but
could have stubs like searching for a
product, adding to a cart, checking out.
And um, then it'll also write a website
specific implementation of it like this
one for Amazon. Then when it's
interacting with a different site, you
could have some metadata or you could
even just have the language model
trigger that this particular concrete
implementation no longer applies. and
then you'll write a different
instantiation of the abstract class. And
they show that this helps too. Um, this
is also nice because it gives you a way
to have like a large number of specific
skills, but only have a subset of them
be active at a given time that are
actually relevant. So, this kind of
makes sense, right? It's, you know, just
a software engineering best practice
that's also applied to agents.
Okay. Uh, yeah, we talked about all this
already. um you guys had a good sense of
the the pros and cons of each of these
types of representation, but it's
helpful to know that, you know, the
skills standard allows you to combine
both and um there's a lot of research to
be done on the best way to combine these
representations together. Um like uh
said,
okay, so we'll go quickly through a few
papers um on different kind of like
parts of this skill life cycle. This is
a really open research topic of like
what are the best ways to induce and
manage these skills. Um you'll have the
papers for for more details. Um but you
can also explore this in your projects
uh towards the end of the lecture or the
end of the class if you're interested.
Everything we've talked about so far has
been learning from success, but it's
also potentially pretty helpful to learn
from failures. So say that the model
like tries to carry out this task like
um you know searching for Bluetooth
headphones. Um but for this particular
website they sort of have like their
search terms are or rather than and so
you get a list of everything that's
Bluetooth or headphones or a Sony. This
is a real example from this reasoning
bench paper from Google. So you get like
5,000 results and the agent just breaks
on this like it has to pagionate through
all of these 5,000 results. it does, you
know, it loses track of what the task is
and it fails. But if we observe that um
failed trajectory sort of in the
reflection style way, we could uh
produce some text that gives guidance on
how to avoid it in the future. Like
saying um we should give a more specific
search term rather than this more
general one and we should you know have
like a larger number of items displayed
so the model gets more in its context
window at once. And this paper um
generally uses the same framework as
like uh agent workflow memory, agent
skill induction, but instead of just
having these kind of abstractions of the
correct trajectories, it generates this
text feedback um which um is applicable
to failed trajectories too and is also
you know the kind of thing that you
would write in a skill yourself um if
you were writing one
and they find that this is pretty
helpful. So these are different like
types of memory. Um so synapse uses
trajectories
like full trajectories with all of the
actions and observations all the tool
calls and messages. Um this is agent
workflow memory that uses these slightly
abstracted parts of trajectories. And
this is their approach that uses these
text descriptions of strategies and um
adding and negatives going you know
adding and negative examples as inputs
to the memory. um uh doesn't improve
performance when you're using either
trajectories or
um workflows, but does improve
substantially when you have sort of
these text descriptions, which kind of
makes sense given the example we saw
before because you can describe in a
general way how not to fail
rather than remembering and conditioning
on those failures.
Another important thing to think about
is we're deciding whether to store
trajectories um you know store things in
the memory or what type of strategies to
infer from the examples based on whether
we judged the example to be successful
or not. That's in most of this work
using a model as a judge that looks at
the final state of the trajectory, looks
at the task that you were trying to
solve and predicts does it seem like I
got it correct or not. So a really good
question to ask here is what you know
how much does the quality of that judge
affect the performance of the algorithm
because we know the judges aren't
perfect. Um this paper reasoning bank
controlled for this. So they um run
their methods with a perfect judge. Um
and they also like to so they use kind
of the ground truth knowledge of whether
it succeeded or not. Um but then they
add some noise into that and so you're
able to control um the accuracy the
simulated accuracy of judging this
trajectory and the performance does fall
off but they find there's kind of a
sweet spot where um you do get
improvements from the memory um and uh
there's sort of a widish range of
accuracies where using the judge to
induce the memory is helpful but there's
definitely room to do future work here.
Okay. And uh yeah, with the last few
minutes, um I want to come back to we
had a question before about does having
more skills than are necessary um
potentially hurt performance? And we
also had a question about like um we're
if we're retrieving skills from a set um
does that retriever matter? Like does
the quality of that retriever matter? So
um there were some nice ablation
experiments in this reasoning bank paper
that uh control um how many experiences
you are retrieving from the memory that
you have and they show that performance
does fall out fall off as you have more
available. Um so this could be because
of a couple different factors. So um you
know maybe you just haven't run your
agent on that many tasks and maybe
there's nothing relevant in your memory.
So putting more stuff in is just bound
to be irrelevant. That would be sort of
like just a fundamental limitation of
this approach applied in that setting.
Right? You can only learn if there's
some similarities between the things
you're learning from and the things
you're applying to. But it could also be
like a limitation of the model itself.
Maybe the model gets thrown off by
having more things available in the
context window. That could potentially
be fixed by training the model, right?
To be better at not being distracted by
irrelevant context, to be better at
reasoning about what's actually
relevant.
And um yeah, it can also potentially be
useful to uh explicitly reduce the size
of your memory um so that there's less
of a burden on the language model to
select from the things that are in it.
And um we did some work on this that
sort of uses like a caching type
approach um that you just look and see
how often has a particular item in your
memory been used in the past um and if
it hasn't been used very frequently,
you'll drop it.
And this can you know improve this
efficiency of the approaches quite a bit
because you don't have to put as much in
your context window but can also improve
their success if the models are getting
distracted by things that are
irrelevant.
Yeah. And the very last thing that we'll
cover is so all of this was in some ways
a little bit ad hoc, right? Like we were
just having the language model look at
these past experiences and then produce
a skill which would be put in the memory
and used in the future. But we're just
like prompting the language model to
predict things that seem like they might
be useful in the future. And a really
natural question is could you just train
the language model to do that directly?
Um you can. Um this is a direction
that's starting to be explored just
really recently. So these papers um are
just appearing at you know just appeared
at ACL um this year. But the basic idea
here is that we're going to do
reinforcement learning over multiple
tasks seen in sequence. So this online
learning setting that we've been
covering for evaluation, we're also
going to run training on it. We'll get
multiple similar tasks in sequence and
we'll be building up the memory. um in
the same way that we've been doing
before by inducing skills from the
experience and using the memory on the
future tasks. So this is a very complex,
you know, process, right? Like we're
using a couple different models here. Uh
we're storing things in a memory. We're
retrieving those. We're using them. But
the good thing is reinforcement learning
doesn't care. You can just apply
reinforcement learning to complex
non-ifferiable processes like this.
We'll have a couple lectures that show
you how. Um and you can get reward from
uh
did this second task succeed and did it
use tasks that were induced in the past.
So you can just do reinforcement
learning on this reward being trained on
um skill induction on sequences of
similar tasks. And um there's a couple
papers that have explored this. They
both find that this is helpful. And uh
one of them had this interesting result
that um it helps to improve success if
you also include this reward term that
incentivizes reuse of the skills. So you
could also imagine like introducing
other sorts of reward terms that like
minimize the size of the skill libraries
that you've induced to try to you know
kind of keep things regularized and not
overfit too much. Um I think there's a
lot of interesting like feature work
that could be explored here.
And um yeah that's uh that's all the
time that we have. Uh but uh hopefully
you got a sense for the way that skills
are induced and also written. Um you'll
apply those in your projects and you can
explore them in the research projects
too. I'll stick around for a few minutes
if folks have any questions.